

Profile

I can call myself the "old guard" of software development, yet always open to change. I have years of practical experience with different technology. I keep improving my skills on a daily basis and learning new tricks "on-site" as I solve the problems of an ongoing successful business. I feel the pains of an IT business and at the same time understand know all ins and outs of software development. My motto is, 'Never say "I can't," rather "Give me some more time".

Employment History

CTO, WellDone Creative Software, London, UK / Kyiv, Ukraine (remotely)

2009 - PRESENT

12 years of successful technical management and hands-on software development at a small private company:

- Developing and managing corporate websites and web applications (PHP, MySQL, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, D3,js).
- Developing a Windows VPS hosting service, including a billing system and a management console (Proxmox, KVM, Powershell, PHP).
- Designing and managing a ~1 Tb statistical data service (MySQL, Clickhouse, PHP, D3.js, Node.js, API).
- Developing native libraries for the company's software products (C/C++, SQLite, OpenSSL).
- Integration of the company's products and apps with third-party services, platforms, and APIs: Stipe, PayPal, SMS gateway, mass mail / ticket system / CRM, MODx, SMF, Cloudflare, several APIs (JSON, XML/SOAP, REST).

Head of Internet Services, Kits Telecom ISP, Zaporizhzhya, Ukraine

2004 - 2007

Supervised a team of systems engineers and network administrators in the rolling out of a new cable Internet service provider. The company was later acquired by a national ISP.

Head of Web Development, Market ISP, Zaporizhzhya, Ukraine

2004 - 2005

Managed a team of web developers and designers working on commercial websites.

Senior Full Stack Developer, Marka ISP, Zaporizhzhya, Ukraine

1999 - 2003

Started as a junior Full Stack developer and was promoted to the senior position. Building business presentation websites, online stores, e-commerce websites, chat rooms.

Layout designer, QA specialist, Telenedelya, Zaporizhzhya, Ukraine

1995 - 2000

Created newspaper layouts and automated their design and testing; supervised certain publishing tasks at the local newspaper.

Education

School of Small and Medium Business, Kyiv, Ukraine

201

Took an extended course in business planning and resourcing.

Bachelor degree, Zaporizhzhe National Technical University, Ukraine

1991 - 1996

Electronics design engineer.

Location

Kyiv, Ukraine +380679718672 sergiy@savostin.com

22 Dec 1974

Links

<u>Facebook</u> LinkedIn

Skills

Node.js

PHP

Javascript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, D3.js

MySQL/MariaDB, SQLite, Clickhouse

C / C++, WinAPI

Nginx, Apache, php-fpm, pm2, bash, Git, Docker, DevOps

Virtualbox, Proxmox, KVM

Linux, Windows, MacOS

Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Sketch

Languages

Russian

Ukrainian

English

Hobbies

Hiking, cycling, traveling, volleyball, dioramas and miniatures modelling, writing music, books publishing.